LAID-BACK CAMP SEASON 3
Processed by 繁化姬 dict-121252ff-r1052 @ 2024/11/13 01:07:42 | https://zhconvert.org
RAIN CAMP
(雨天露营)
I'll be staying for one night, and I'll be riding my motorbike over.
要住一晚 我会骑机车过去
Are you sure?
确定没问题吗
It looks like it might rain later.
等一下好像会下雨哦
Rain?
下雨?
But I checked the weather forecast before I left.
但我出门前有看天气预报
The forecast said it wouldn't rain,
虽然天气预报是说应该不会下雨
but the weather in the mountains can be unpredictable.
但山里的天气可是很多变的
All the other guests have cancelled their reservations too.
预约的客人也全都取消了
Good thing I can rent gear at this campsite.
幸好今天来的是 可以租装备的露营场
Without a tarp on a rainy day,
下雨天没有天幕
you can't do much of anything.
就什么都不能做了
It's raining.
下雨了
It took some time to set up,
虽然要花一些时间立起来
but this is pretty convenient.
但这真的很方便呢
You can't use a camp stove inside the tent,
毕竟在帐篷里不能用登山炉
but under a tarp, it's no problem.
但在天幕底下就没问题了
You hardly see any insects when it's raining.
下雨天几乎不会看到虫子
Makes for a comfy stay-in.
待起来特别舒适呢
CHA MANJU
(茶馒头)
Rain camp.
雨天露营
This campsite at the foot of the mountain
这个山脚下的露营场
is usually fully booked on weekends,
每到六日都会客满 相当难预约
but today there's no one else here.
但现在却一个人都没有
Guess a rainy day's the only time
想独占知名的露营场
you can have this campsite all to yourself.
就只能趁下雨天的时候了呢
I even get this view of Mt. Fuji all to myself.
还能独占富士山
Rain camp.
雨天露营
This is nice,
像这样一边听着雨声 一边看书
"ARE CRYPTIDS REAL?" reading a book
(未确认生物真的存在吗)
with the sound of the rain in the back.
感觉很有气氛 真不错呢
T-Tsuchinoko?
槌…槌之子?
Hello.
你好
H…hello.
你…你好
Y…Yeti?
雪…雪男?
No, I'm a snowman.
不 我是雪人
Rain camp.
雨天露营
Since I can't start a campfire,
因为不能点篝火
trying out things I normally wouldn't do
尝试一些平时不会做的事
is another way to enjoy a rain camp.
也是一种享受雨天露营的方式
So
所以
with some wood, I decided to
我决定用刀子削木柴
whittle a spoon
做了一只汤匙
If I can make little things like this on the spot…
如果能当场做出这种小东西
I forgot to bring a spoon!
忘记带汤匙了
Rin, you're amazing!
小凛 你好厉害哦
The neck of the spoon
不过 汤子的脖子?
is tricky, though.
果然有点难削耶
I just couldn't get the curve right with a knife.
弧度部分就真的没办法 用刀弄出来了
I'll use the right tool to fix it when I get home.
等回家后 再用雕刻刀加工一下吧
Now then, what should I do next?
那么 接下来要做什么呢
Rain camp.
雨天露营
Going for a walk in the forest on a rainy day is nice.
雨天在森林散步也挺不错的
Don't have to worry
而且在森林里面
about the rain getting too heavy either.
也不用担心雨下太大
Maybe I should head back.
还是回去吧
Rain camp.
雨天露营
There's something special about eating curry ramen
用自己削的筷子吃咖喱方便面
with chopsticks I carved myself.
感觉别有一番风味呢
Is the hook loose
是因为被雨淋湿
because it got wet from the rain?
所以挂勾松脱了吗
COLLAPSE
(倒塌)
Rain camp.
雨天露营
Rin, it's raining. Is everything okay on your end?
小凛 外面下雨了 你那边还好吗
Nadeshiko.
抚子
It looks like the clouds are starting to clear.
乌云好像快飘走了
Everything's going just swell…
完全没问题
…or not.
其实根本问题一大堆
Rin, you're really something
下雨天居然还去露营
for camping in the rain.
凛真厉害呢
If it were me, I'd definitely have given up.
要是我的话 肯定就放弃了
What do you even do while it's raining?
雨天露营 不会无事可做吗
Even in the rain, you find ways to enjoy it.
就算下雨 也要享受其中
That's what camping is all about, right?
所谓的露营不就是这样吗
Sounding like a pro!
好像专家哦
That's a real pro for you.
确实是专家呢
I'm going to turn in for the night.
我差不多要睡了
Good night.
晚安
GOOD NIGHT
(晚安)
Like a pro, huh?
像专家吗
Rain camp.
雨天露营
There were a lot of issues,
虽然会遇到许多麻烦
but I guess this view makes it all worth it.
但如果能看到这个景象 或许还算不错
There's still so much about camping
这世上还有很多
that I've got to learn.
我不知道的露营方式呢
Rain camp.
雨天露营